tmbc.com 2016-10-30

# Privacy Policy - TMBC - StandOut

THE MARCUS BUCKINGHAM COMPANY PRIVACY POLICY  
Last Modified on March 20, 2015.

**Internet Privacy Policy**  
Technology and new marketing practices have increased the amount of customer information collected and shared in today’s marketplace. The Marcus Buckingham Company maintains a firm commitment to protect the privacy of the information you share with us; the following document will disclose the privacy principles and practices we follow.  
This Privacy Policy is effective as of the date set forth above and is only applicable to the website where this Privacy Policy is posted (the “Site”). This Privacy Policy is not applicable to any other website that you may be able to access from the Site, including the StandOut web site, which may have its own data collection and use practices and policies. By visiting the Site, you consent to the collection, use, storage, deletion and disclosure of information relating to you as set forth in this Privacy Policy.

**Information Collected**  
The Marcus Buckingham Company, as a part of offering services on this Site, collects certain information. Information is collected in two ways: (1) automatically via the operation of the Site’s servers, software, and the web browser you use to connect to these services, and (2) voluntarily when you directly share your information with us via input from you to forms and other features of the Site. The information we collect is limited to such information as is necessary to provide you with the highest level of customer service, and with access to those services you have chosen to utilize on the Site.

Automatically collected information includes your “IP Address”, the physical location from which you accessed our Site, and certificate information from your browser, which is used by secure areas of our Site. We do not associate any such information with records containing any personal information submitted to us, so you remain anonymous when you browse our Site. Anonymous browsing information may be used to gather broad demographic information. This information may be aggregated to measure the number of visits, average time spent, page views, and other statistics about users of our Site. We also may use this data to monitor our Site’s performance, to analyze how users use the Site and to make our Site easier and more convenient to use.

Voluntary information collected may include information you provide to us when you use any of our online tools, including signing up for a webinar or demo, when you send us email or use the “Contact Us” form, when you make a purchase, or when you use future products and tools such as may be offered from time to time. We may collect personal information such as your name, e-mail address, phone number, company name, zip code and state. If you make a purchase, we will also collect billing information, such as billing name, address, phone number and credit/debit card information.

**Google Analytics**  
The Site uses Google Analytics to help us learn about who visits the Site and what pages are being viewed.

**Use of Collected Information**  
We employ cookies in certain areas of the Site to allow us to provide information to make your online experience more convenient. For example, when you return to the Site after logging in, cookies provide information to the Site so that the Site will remember who you are on subsequent visits, speeding up or enhancing your experience of the Site by, for instance, tailoring content to you. Cookies also prevent items placed in a shopping basket from disappearing by the time you checkout.

We also employ web beacons to capture statistical usage information. We do not use web beacons to collect personal information about you. We may correlate this information to a user to personalize user experience and for statistical analysis of user experiences on our web pages.

Voluntarily provided information is used to provide you with the products and services you request. We also may use contact information we collect to communicate with you, to respond to your questions and requests, and to send you information about our company or promotional materials concerning our partners. Should you not desire to receive this information, you may contact as via email at customerservice@tmbc.com, call us at 323-302-9810, or notify us in writing to The Marcus Buckingham Company, 8350 Wilshire Blvd Suite 200, Beverly Hills, CA 90211. For further information regarding opt-out, please see the section on “Communication Choices” below.

Financial information, such as credit card numbers and billing codes, may be used to bill you for services or products received. Identification information, such as account numbers, user ids, and passwords, may be used to positively identify you to our computer systems and to customize your experience of the Site to your individual preferences.  
We will share personal information if we have a good faith belief that (i) access, use, preservation or disclosure of such information is reasonably necessary to satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process, such as a court order or subpoena, or a request by law enforcement or governmental authorities, (ii) such action is appropriate to enforce our Terms of Use our Site, including any investigation of potential violations thereof, (iii) such action is necessary to detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues associated with our Site, or (iv) such action is appropriate to protect the rights, property or safety of The Marcus Buckingham Company, its employees, users of our Site or others.

If we become involved in a merger, acquisition or other transaction involving the sale of some or all of our assets, user information, including personal information collected from you through your use of the our Site, could be included in the transferred assets. Should such an event occur, we will use reasonable means to notify you through email and/or a prominent notice on the Site.

We may share your personal information with service providers that we engage for the purpose of processing information on our and your behalf. For example, we may partner with other companies to process payments for the online store. Additionally, we may partner with other companies to process, analyze, and/or store data. While providing services for us, these companies may access your personal information. To the extent applicable, we require these entities to comply with this Privacy Policy and appropriate confidentiality and security measures.

Except as set forth in this Privacy Policy, The Marcus Buckingham Company does not share the personal information collected online with any person or entity other than those affiliated with The Marcus Buckingham Company.

**Access to Information**  
Only those employees who need and require customer information to perform their duties are authorized to access customer information. Information shared with business partners is limited to only that information necessary to allow them to provide you with information regarding services and products in which you may have an interest. Additionally, we require that companies we select as business partners honor our privacy requirements in the handling of customer information we provide to them.

Occasionally, we may be compelled by law to provide information to requesting legal entities or agencies. If we receive a subpoena or similar legal process demanding release of any information about you, we will generally attempt to notify you before we comply with the request (when practicable or unless we believe we are prohibited from doing so). Except as required by law or as described above, we do not share information with requesting outside parties, including government agencies.

**Protecting Your Information**  
We take our responsibility to protect the privacy and confidentiality of customer information very seriously. The personal information that you provide to us is stored on servers, which are located in secured facilities and protected by protocols and procedures designed to ensure the security of such information. We have procedures in place and observe strict security practices that limit employee access to your personal information to those employees with a specific business reason to know this information.  
However, no server, computer or communications network or system, or data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect user information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or through the use of our Site and you acknowledge and agree that you provide such information and engage in such transmissions at your own risk. Once we receive a transmission from you, we will endeavor to maintain its security on our systems.

**Linking to Other Internet Sites**  
Our site may contain direct links, whether through a logo or URL, to websites operated by our business partners and other third party entities. These third party websites may collect information about you when you visit them or otherwise communicate with them, and their privacy policies may differ from our Privacy Policy. When you have clicked on such link to a different website, our Privacy Policy no longer applies and you must review the privacy policies of the third party to see how your personal information will be handled on their website.

**Communication Choices**  
You may elect to stop receiving information from us, and/or from our partners, at any time, (i) by adjusting your email preferences in your account settings, or (ii) by notifying us via email at customerservice@tmbc.com or in writing to The Marcus Buckingham Company, 8350 Wilshire Blvd Suite 200, Beverly Hills, CA 90211. Once you have opted out of further communications, you will not receive emails, catalogs, or telephone solicitations from us, and we will not share your information with our partners. You may continue to receive information from business partners, as we have no control over their sources or use of contact information.

**Review and Change of Information**  
We are committed to maintaining complete and accurate information about our customers. You may review information that we retain on you and your relationship with us, and we will promptly correct any and all errors in that information. If you find any information that we maintain about you or your accounts to be incorrect, please notify us immediately, either by telephone at 323-302-9810, or in writing at The Marcus Buckingham Company, 8350 Wilshire Blvd Suite 200, Beverly Hills, CA 90211. Please do not contact us via normal email; we cannot guarantee the security of any information you send us via normal email.

**Mediation**  
You agree that, in the event any dispute or claim arises out of or relating to this Privacy Policy, you and The Marcus Buckingham Company will attempt in good faith to negotiate a written resolution of the matter directly between the parties. If you reside in the United States, you agree that if the matter remains unresolved for forty-five (45) days after notification (via certified mail or personal delivery) that a dispute exists, all parties shall join in mediation services in Los Angeles, California with a mutually agreed mediator in an attempt to resolve the dispute. Should you file any arbitration claims, or any administrative or legal actions without first having attempted to resolve the matter by mediation, then you agree that you will not be entitled to recover attorneys’ fees, even if you would otherwise be entitled to them.

**Dispute Resolution for Residents of the European Union**  
If you are a resident of the European Union, in the event that you have any dispute or claim arising out of or relating to this Privacy Policy, you may report your claim to the European Union Data Protection Authorities located in your jurisdiction.

**Children**  
Products of The Marcus Buckingham Company are not routinely marketed to children, and no age verification outside of the provision of a credit card occurs on this site. Provision of a valid credit card is taken as evidence that an individual is authorized to purchase products and services from the Site.

**Contact**  
If you have questions regarding this Privacy Policy, or the commercial practices of or your dealings with this website or The Marcus Buckingham Company, please contact:  
The Marcus Buckingham Company  
8350 Wilshire Blvd  
Suite 200  
Beverly Hills, California 90211  
Attn: Internet Systems Administrator

**Notification of Changes**  
This Privacy Policy may change from time to time and we will post all changes on the Site.
